we've created a file
age.rb and we want our program to ask
the user
how old they are and then display to
them
how old they will be in 10 20
30 and 40 years so the first thing we
want to do
is prompt the user to enter their age
we'll invoke the put us method
and display a message to the user asking
how old they are
now we want to pause program execution
and allow the user to enter their age
and we'll use the get s method to do
that
and the chomp method to remove the
newline character at the end of that
user input
let's store that user input in a local
variable called age
so let's run our code as it is now
we'll input 20
in our program ends
the next step is to display a message
back to the user
so let's just start with the first
calculation which is
in 10 years you will be
and below that will output the age
so we'll reference our age variable and
we want to output the return value
of adding 10 to the user's age
let's run our code and see if we get the
expected behavior
so we've successfully displayed the
first line of our message
but the code on line 4 of our program
raised an error
and if we read our error message it
tells us no
implicit conversion of integer into
string
the error was raised when we tried to
add our age to the integer 10.
all user input comes in as a string
so our local variable age references the
string
20. in order for our program to work
properly
and perform the addition on line 4 we
need to convert that user input to an
integer
and we can do that by calling the 2i
method
on the user input string now the user
input is stored in the variable age as
an integer
let's run our code again
and this time we see the appropriate
output
so we also want to output the user's age
in 20
30 and 40 years
we'll run our code one more time
and we see the expected output
be sure to remember that user input
always comes in as a string